<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Meniere</string>

    <string name="MyMeniere">My Ménière</string>
    <string name="aboutMeniere">About Ménière</string>
    <string name="utilities">Utilities</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="title_activity_spalsh">SpalshActivity</string>
    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="textSplash1">MÈNIÈRE</string>

    <!-- Acciones dialogos -->
    <string name="dialogoGuardar">Guardar</string>
    <string name="positiveTxtOk">Ok</string>
    <string name="negativeTxtCancel">Cancel</string>


    <!-- My Meniere -->
    <string name="titleNewEvent">New event</string>
    <string name="min">Min.</string>
    <string name="max">Max.</string>
    <string name="episodes">Episodes:</string>
    <string name="duration">Duration:</string>
    <string name="vertigoIntensity">Vertigo intensity:</string>
    <string name="limitation">Intensity limitation:</string>
    <string name="stress">Stress level:</string>
    <string name="hearingLoss">Hearing loss</string>
    <string name="tinnitus">Tinnitus</string>
    <string name="earFullness">Ear fullness</string>
    <string name="headache">Headache</string>
    <string name="photophobia">Photophobia</string>
    <string name="phonophobia">Phonophobia</string>
    <string name="visualSymptoms">Visual symptoms</string>
    <string name="tumarkin">Tumarkin</string>
    <string name="menstruation">Menstruation</string>
    <string name="nausea">Nausea</string>
    <string name="vomiting">Vomiting</string>
    <string name="instability">Instability</string>
    <string name="instabilityIntensity">Instability intensity:</string>
    <string name="headacheProperties">Headache properties</string>
    <string name="NA">N/A</string>
    <string name="mild">Mild</string>
    <string name="moderate">Moderate</string>
    <string name="severe">Severe</string>
    <string name="oneSide">One side</string>
    <string name="wholeHead">Whole Head</string>
    <string name="throbbing">Throbbing</string>
    <string name="tightening">Tigthening</string>
    <string name="eventTriggers">Event triggers</string>
    <string name="weather">Weather</string>
    <string name="sunny">Sunny</string>
    <string name="cloudy">Cloudy</string>
    <string name="storm">Storm</string>
    <string name="sleep">Sleep</string>
    <string name="excelent">Excelent</string>
    <string name="regular">Regular</string>
    <string name="poor">Poor</string>
    <string name="physicalActivity">Physical activity</string>
    <string name="high">High</string>
    <string name="medium">Medium</string>
    <string name="low">Low</string>
    <string name="habitExcess">Habit - Excess</string>
    <string name="salt">Salt</string>
    <string name="caffeine">Caffeine</string>
    <string name="alcohol">Alcohol</string>
    <string name="tobacco">Tobacco</string>
    <string name="sugar">Sugar</string>
    <string name="myNotes">My notes</string>
    <string name="backSymps">Background Symptoms</string>
    <string name="dizzinessDis">Dizziness disability:</string>
    <string name="inestabilityDis">Inestability disability:</string>
    <string name="visualBlurDis">Visual blur disability:</string>
    <string name="headPressure">Head Pressure:</string>
    <string name="explanation">Disability Scale: (Shepard et al., 1990)\n\n0: No disability; negligible symptoms\n1: No disability; bothersome symptoms\n2: Mild disability; performs usual work/duties, but symptoms interfere with outside activities\n3: Moderate disability; symptoms disrupt performance of both usual work and outside activities\n4: Recent severe disability; on medical leave or hard to change job because of symptoms\n5: Estabilished severe disability; unable to work for over 1 year or estabilished permanent disability with compensations payments)</string>

    <string name="selectionErrorTitle">Selection error</string>
    <string name="selectionErrorMessagePassDay">Your should select today\'s date to add a new event.</string>
    <string name="newEventErrorTitle">New event error</string>
    <string name="newEventErrorMessageDayHasEvent">This day already has events. You only can add one event per day.</string>
    <string name="addEpisodeTitle">Add more episodes</string>
    <string name="addEpisodeContent">You have selected to add more episodes. Please enter the number of episodes for today. You must to summarize your symptoms in the other fields of this section</string>
    <string name="hearingLossSwitchTitle">More data is needed</string>
    <string name="hearingLossSwitchContent">You selected some auditive symptoms. Please specify where these auditive symptoms mainly occurred.</string>
    <string name="infoVisualTitle">Items info</string>
    <string name="infoVisualContent">Visual symptoms: Visual sensations that occur mainly before the attack.\n\nTumarkin: Sudden fall with no previous warning or provocative factor and without vertigo or loss of consciousness.</string>

    <string name="mandatoryFieldsContent">Data is not enought to add a new record, please set more data or press \'back\' button.</string>

    <!--Login-->
    <string name="userEditText">E-mail</string>
    <string name="newUserEditText">New E-mail</string>
    <string name="passEditText">Password</string>
    <string name="newPassEditText">New password</string>
    <string name="currentPassEditText">Current password</string>
    <string name="confirmPassEditText">Confirm password</string>
    <string name="newConfirmPassEditText">Confirm new password</string>
    <string name="invalidEmail">Invalid E-mail.</string>
    <string name="differentConfirmPass">Confirm password is different.</string>
    <string name="invalidPass">Invalid password.</string>
    <string name="registerSuccess">Register successfully</string>
    <string name="emptyEmail">Enter E-mail</string>
    <string name="emptyPass">Enter password</string>
    <string name="singUpBtn">Sing up</string>
    <string name="loginUpBtn">Login</string>
    <string name="saveBtn">Save</string>
    <string name="rememberPassInfo">Remember password</string>
    <string name="resetEmailPassInfo">Reset E-mail or password</string>
    <string name="registerInfo">Please sing up with a valid E-mail to allow us to send back your password in case you forget it.</string>
    <string name="loginInfo">To protect your personal data this section is password protected.\n\nEnter password below.</string>
    <string name="rememberPassContent">We will send your password to </string>
    <string name="editUserDataInfo">Write current password below.</string>


    <!-- Hearing diary -->
    <string name="titleNewEntry">Nueva audición</string>
    <string name="oidoIzquierdo">Oído Izquierdo</string>
    <string name="oidoDerecho">Oído Derecho</string>
    <string name="frecuencia05">0.5kHz:</string>
    <string name="frecuencia1">1kHz:</string>
    <string name="frecuencia2">2kHz:</string>
    <string name="frecuencia4">4kHz:</string>
    <string name="frecMasMenos">±</string>
    <string name="enCrisis">En crisis</string>

    <!-- Tab one -->
    <string name="txtNewEvent">New Event</string>
    <string name="txtSeeSelection">See Selection</string>
    <string name="txtMonthReview">Month Review</string>
    <string name="txtFocusToday">Back Today</string>
    <string name="txtMonthEvents">Month Events:</string>

    <!-- Tab Four -->
    <string name="txtUserGuide">Guia de uso</string>
    <string name="txtAuthors">Autores</string>
    <string name="txtFrameworks">Frameworks</string>
    <string name="txtVisitWeb">Visitar Web</string>

    <!-- Tab thre -->
    <string name="txtHearingDiary">Diario Auditivo</string>
    <string name="txtHealthyHabits">Buenos Hábitos</string>
    <string name="txtRateMe">¡Puentúame!</string>

    <string-array name="arrayQuestions">
        <item>WHAT IS MÉNIÈRE’S DISEASE?</item>
        <item>HOW COMMON IS IT?</item>
        <item>WHAT IS THE CAUSE OF MD?</item>
        <item>WHAT ARE THE SYMPTOMS OF MD?</item>
        <item>HOW IS A DIAGNOSIS MADE?</item>
        <item>HOW IS MD TREATED?</item>
        <item>HOW CAN I COPE WITH MD?</item>
        <item>MORE INFO ABOUT MD?</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="arrayAnswers" formatted="false">
        <item>Ménière’s syndrome is a chronic inner-ear disorder characterized by frequent episodes of spontaneous vertigo and fluctuating hearing loss in one or sometimes both ears, tinnitus (ringing in the ears), and a feeling of fullness in the ear.
            When we can point to a recognized cause for these symptoms, it is called Ménière’s syndrome. However, in many cases it is often difficult to find a cause at all, so in theses cases it is coined Ménière’s disease (MD).</item>
        <item>Although MD is considered the third most common cause of vertigo, after benign paroxysmal positional vertigo and vestibular migraine, it is a rare disease. In the United States, it is estimated that approximately 615,000 individuals are currently diagnosed with Ménière’s disease and that 45,500 cases are newly diagnosed each year.
            MD commonly begins between 30 and 50 years of age, and the condition is often found to affect a higher proportion of females. Both ears are affected in 25–40% of sufferers. If the condition is found in patients of the same family of one or two generations apart, it is considered familial MD.
            Migraine and autoimmune diseases (systemic lupus erythematous, psoriasis, or rheumatoid arthritis) are common in patients with MD.
        </item>
        <item>The cause of MD is unknown although allergies, autoimmunity, and genetic factors are supposed to be involved. Furthermore, one or more suspected environmental factors may trigger the disease. Somehow, an excess of a fluid in the inner ear, known as endolymph, causes an expansion of some structures of the inner ear termed endolymphatic hydrops.
        </item>
        <item>Symptoms may vary over time and are often experienced differently from one patient to another. Vertigo is the most disabling symptom, commonly described as a spinning sensation, made worse by head movements and is accompanied by nausea, vomiting, and sweating. Spells of vertigo appear spontaneously lasting several hours and, when they subside,
            patients complain of a lack of balance for some days.These spells of vertigo often begin with tinnitus and aural fullness, followed a little later by a loss of hearing in the affected ear. But, as the disease progresses over time, hearing worsens with each attack with the previous hearing level not fully recovered. Eventually, deafness becomes
            permanent and no longer fluctuates.Some patients report sudden falls with no previous warning or trigger, and without vertigo, loss of consciousness, or other neurologic symptoms. We refer to these episodes as crises of Tumarkin.Headaches occur in more than 40% of Ménière’s attacks, and migraine-type headaches are felt in 8% of patients during
            episodes of vertigo.Numerous factors have been known to trigger MD attacks, including stress, sleep deprivation, some foods, allergens, change of atmospheric pressure, and hormonal changes such us the period.The frequency of attacks is highly unpredictable and varies greatly from patient to patient. As time progresses, the frequency of these
            attacks usually decreases, and hearing loss becomes permanent, as does the tinnitus.</item>
        <item>There is currently no precise way of testing for MD, therefore diagnosis is determined through a patient´s symptoms and any signs perceived by a medical practitioner. A hearing test is needed to determine the existence of hearing loss in the affected ear, and its type. Balance function tests such as caloric tests and/or a video head impulse test, are commonly performed. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is routinely called for to rule out other causes of vertigo.
        </item>
        <item>MD treatment is often issued in two main ways
            Treatment given as and when a patient suffers a spell.
            Preventive treatment, usually in the form of daily medication. While suffering a spell of MD, you may require medication to alleviate nausea, vomiting or feelings of vertigo. Depending on the impact on your quality of life, a preventive treatment may also be required. Preventive treatment comprises:
            dietary changes (an increase in water intake and a low-salt diet) and lifestyle changes which include avoiding caffeine, smoking and alcohol, avoiding stressful situations, getting regular sleep and doing light exercise
            oral medication (diuretics, betahistine)
            intratympanic injection with either gentamicin or corticosteroids
            and in some extreme cases surgical procedures.
            The diverse nature of MD could explain the difference in response to a treatment between one person and the next. Other treatment options are hearing aids, cochlear implants, and the Meniett device.</item>
        <item>MD has a high impact on healthrelated quality of life. Along with hearing loss comes an inability to discriminate between different phonemes.
            Oftentimes a rise in volume will not improve comprehension and may even cause greater difficulties in understanding speech.
            As you can imagine, this often causes some limitations in your daily routines.
            Your doctor can advise you and clarify any aspect related to the disease and its treatment.
            Relaxation techniques and cognitive behavioral therapy can help you.
            Selfhelp groups, such as the Menieres Society in UK or ASMES in Spain, can offer you support.
            Today, MD is considered incurable but research efforts are becoming more successful and we are gaining a better understanding of the disease.
            So, there is a hope for the development of a specific treatment through our continued investigations.
            Please help us with our ongoing efforts to find a cure for this debilitating disease.
        </item>
        <item>links</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="arrayTituloHabitos">
        <item>OVERVIEW</item>
        <item>DIET</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE CHANGES</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE: EXERCISE</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE: SLEEP</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE: STRESS</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="arrayDescripcionHabitos" formatted="false">
        <item>DIETARY CHANGES AND LIFESTYLE MODIFICATIONS
            Making some changes to your diet and adopting good lifestyle habits are two important means of preventive treatment of MD.
        </item>
        <item>The initial aim is to avoid all the common triggers of MD, but once your symptoms have improved you can slowly reintroduce them trying to identify your personal triggers.
            The most important dietary recommendation is a high-water intake and a low sodium diet. Some Japanese researchers have found that a water intake of 35 mL/kg per day (about 2 litres and a half if you are 70 kg) may improve the symptoms of MD. Very low sodium mineral water is a good option. We also advise a sodium intake between 1.5-2g per day (less than a teaspoon of table salt). Therefore, we recommend removing the use of salt at the table and reducing the consumption of foods with a high-sodium content like processed or cured meats (bacon, sausages, ham) and frozen meals, canned foods, fast food and potato chips. We also recommend avoiding food containing monosodium glutamate, a flavor enhancer commonly added to Chinese food.
            It is also advisable to eat at regular times and not to skip meals.
            Coffee and other caffeine-containing food and drink like tea and chocolate should be reduced to one cup of coffee a day, as should alcohol with a limit of a glass of wine or half a pint of beer per day.
        </item>
        <item>Try to adopt healthy habits to your daily life. A systematic approach to your life helps to maintain daily routines which may prevent vertigo attacks.
            Exercise regularly, establish regular sleeping habits and think of ways to reduce stress. Try to limit caffeine and alcohol intake.
            Keep in mind that smoking is often not just a habit but also an addiction, so if you have MD, it is a good opportunity to try to quit.
        </item>
        <item>Be active and do some light to moderate physical exercise. Try going for a walk for 30 minutes at least every day or playing some sport regularly. Dancing, aerobics, Pilates and tai chi are also good options.</item>
        <item>Try these tips below to help you to form healthy sleep habits. In order to maintain at least 7 hours of sleep per night, try keeping a
            regular sleep schedule which means going to sleep and getting up at the same time every day, including weekends and holidays.
            Consider avoiding naps, especially longer than 20 minutes. Lighter dinners and a reduce fluid intake before bedtime allow for
            ease of sleep. Coffee from late afternoon onward is not advised. Do regular exercise but not too close to bedtime.
        </item>
        <item>Reducing your stress level is easier to said than done, but the question is how to do this. The first step in reducing stress is to identify the cause. Once it is known, first try to change your circumstances. This could mean finding alternatives (manage your time better, change of routines, etc.).  Second, learn ways of avoiding situations that you find stressful. Thirdly, if the above are not possible, try to adapt to your environment.  Ultimately, sometimes it is necessary to accept that there are things we just can’t change. Take then a deep breath and try to stay calm.
            Take note of your negative thoughts, erroneous beliefs and attitudes that contribute to your stress. This is particularly important when dealing with tinnitus. Do the same with erratic behaviors and emotions. Professional guidance may be necessary to change these negative trains of thought and to develop healthy coping strategies. Your family, friends and workmates may provide you support. Interact with other people, including people with MD and MD associations.
            Relaxation techniques and mindfulness sessions may be appropriate.</item>

        <item>links</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_authors">AuthorsActivity</string>

    <string-array name="arrayTituloGuia">
        <item>OVERVIEW</item>
        <item>DIET</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE CHANGES</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE: EXERCISE</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE: SLEEP</item>
        <item>LIFESTYLE: STRESS</item>
    </string-array>


    <string name="text_authors">Authors: \n---------\n\n  Juan Manuel Espinosa Jorge Rey Martínez  Collaborators: --------------  
Nicolás Pérez Fernández (Medical Advisor) Ángel Batuecas Caletrío (Medical Advisor) Jose Antonio López Escámez (Medical Advisor) 
Mark Jackson (English Localization) Eva Perendreu (ASMES)  
Original Idea y Design: -----------------------  Juan Manuel Espinosa Jorge Rey Martínez  
iOS Development and Design: ------------------------------  Jorge Rey Martínez Marina González Llorca (iOS Design)    © 2017 Espinosa y Rey</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">MainActivity</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>
